cibc.ca 2019-07-16

# CIBC Digital Privacy Statement | Legal | CIBC

## Effective May 2018

At CIBC, keeping your personal information in confidence is a cornerstone of our business and an integral part of our commitment to service excellence. This Digital Privacy Statement applies to the collection, use or sharing of any personal information collected by CIBC in the course of conducting its business in Canada. This Digital Privacy Statement explains how we collect, use, share and protect personal information collected through your online and mobile activities, including through the use of any CIBC site or other online or electronic technologies such as email and mobile applications. It is consistent with our CIBC Privacy Principles and is in addition to our Privacy Policy and the terms of your agreements with us.

In this Digital Privacy Statement:

"CIBC," "we," "our" and "us" means collectively Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce and its affiliates that offer deposits, loans, mutual funds, securities trading, portfolio management, investment counseling, mortgages, credit cards, trust services, insurance and other products or services.

“Digital” means CIBC Online Banking®, CIBC websites, CIBC mobile sites, CIBC mobile apps or our other electronic technologies. 

"Personal information" or "information" means information about an identifiable individual such as name, email or user IDs.

“Site” means a website and mobile site.  

## What we collect and how we collect it

The type of personal information we collect will depend on various factors, including your digital activities with us. We may collect information in the following ways:

  * **Information you provide us** , through your digital activities such as, mobile apps, applications for products or services, or information that you have inputted into our online tools or calculators. This may include information such as your name, email address, user IDs, passwords, service preference (e.g., language), age, gender, occupation and income range. If you communicate with us online or by email, mobile app or text message, we may collect information contained in that communication, such as your email address or mobile telephone number.
  * **Information that your web browser may provide us** , such as the type of web browser you use (e.g., Internet Explorer, Chrome, Safari or Firefox) or the address of the site you came from.
  * **Information that your devices may provide us** , such as device details (e.g., device ID, model, operating system or device notification status), privacy settings and other device configurations or settings, your geolocation, or your IP address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer or device when you browse the Internet and from which the general geographical location of the device can be derived).
  * **Information obtained using web technologies** , such as cookies and web beacons. Refer to the Web Technologies section below for further information.

##   
How we use information

We may use information for the following purposes:

  * Provide you with our digital products, services and support
  * Communicate with you, including providing alerts that you have requested
  * Personalize your user experience including offering you personalized marketing and offers
  * Better understand your interest in other CIBC products and services
  * Evaluate the effectiveness of our sites, communications, marketing, or offers and promotions
  * Measure site and mobile app usage and improve functionality
  * Enhance digital security including preventing and detecting security threats and criminal activities

Using third-party cookies and other web technologies, CIBC may market CIBC products, services or community initiatives on another company's site (e.g., remarketing). CIBC’s partners and service providers may also use third-party cookies and web technologies to collect and use information from CIBC sites and other third-party sites to assist us in this marketing.  In some cases, the content of this marketing may be based on information we know about you, such as your browsing behavior on CIBC sites and third-party sites where you are shown CIBC ads, your CIBC products and services, and the information you have provided to us. If you access one of these marketing ads, we may also track the response rate, the specific CIBC ad that you selected and the site activity associated with each marketing ad. If you enter a third-party site which has a CIBC ad, we may use cookies to help us identify the site you accessed, but we do not track and create a profile of a user’s behaviour on that site. The response rate data is used to help us plan future online marketing campaigns.  

CIBC may offer mobile applications or services that use location information. If you choose to use such applications or services, CIBC may, if your geolocation device settings allow us, collect information about your location to provide you with the applications or services you request.  

We may also use location information to personalize your user experience including through site or mobile app content, marketing, or offers for products and services. For example, we may use general geographical location derived from your IP address (e.g., city) to customize CIBC site pages for you.

Some services may involve access to information on your device. For example, accessing your contact list can make it easier to use _Interac_  e-Transfer® banking services, or accessing your photos and camera can make it easier to complete a remote cheque deposit on your mobile device. Some services may allow your device and your wearable to communicate with a CIBC app, such as for Apple Watch®.

##   
Protecting your personal information

Protecting the security of your personal information and the financial transactions you conduct online is of utmost importance. We use multiple layers of protection when you access any of our digital products or services, such as digital banking, including:

  * **Web browser encryption:**  all browsers supported by CIBC digital services offer industry standard encryption. This provides a high level of protection for transmitting confidential data over the Internet.
  * **Firewalls:**  we have secure firewalls designed to prevent unauthorized access to our systems.
  * **Monitoring:**  we monitor activity on CIBC digital services to enhance security and to protect your personal information.

CIBC sites may contain links to non-CIBC sites. CIBC is not responsible for the information and privacy practices of these third-party sites. We recommend that you read any such third-party site's privacy policy to learn about its information and privacy practices before you provide any personal information.

##   
Web technologies

CIBC uses various web technologies, including web beacons and cookies.

Web beacons are tiny graphic images we may place on our site pages or in our emails. They may be used to measure such things as response rates to our communications and to help us improve our web pages and promotions.

A cookie is a small file created by a web browser on your computer when you visit a site or a particular page on a site. Cookies collect and store information based upon browsing patterns or information you provide. CIBC uses the following types of cookies on its sites:

  * **Session cookies**  are used during a single site visit and are automatically deleted from your computer when you leave the site. Session cookies perform several critical functions on CIBC sites. For example, they protect your security while you are using digital banking by ensuring that your session is secure while you are signed on. They are also used to ensure that you do not pay the same bill twice during a single banking session.
  * **Persistent cookies**  are used to track site activity over a longer period and remain on your computer until either you choose to delete them or they expire. They are used for a number of purposes on CIBC sites. For example, persistent cookies are used: 
    * To save your CIBC digital banking personal preferences. You must allow persistent cookies if you want your browser to remember such things as your card number, your language preference or your default home page each time you sign on to our digital banking.
    * To collect information about how visitors use our sites (e.g., use of our online tools and services such as retirement calculators) including browsing behaviour. For example, we may measure and track CIBC web and mobile pages viewed or how you came to our sites (e.g., which CIBC online marketing ad you selected, the address of the site that you came from, the sites you are accessing that have CIBC ads, or keywords you searched to find our site).

We may use this information to improve our service, provide a better experience for visitors to our sites and deliver online personalized marketing and offers.

  * **Flash cookies or "locally shared objects"**  are generally used to employ flash or multimedia technology (e.g., video). Software applications may create Flash cookies to store configuration information on your computer so that you may view rich media, such as Flash enabled videos, on CIBC sites. Certain CIBC online tools, such as mortgage calculators, use Flash cookies to retain information inputted by you (e.g., mortgage amount and interest rate), so that you do not need to re-enter this information the next time you use the tool.
  * **Third-party cookies**  are cookies of third-parties that CIBC has permitted to be created when you visit a CIBC site and are used by CIBC for the purposes of CIBC marketing on other companies' sites or to track the effectiveness of such marketing.

##   
Your privacy choices

**  
Cookies:**

You can block or disable third-party cookies in your browser settings so that your browser accepts only first party cookies, which are those cookies belonging to the site you are currently browsing (e.g., cookies from CIBC when you are on CIBC's site).

**Interest-based advertising and opting-out**

Interest-based advertising uses information collected from your browsing behaviour to help predict your preferences and provide you with CIBC-related advertisements that will be more relevant to you on our mobile apps, our website and third-party websites.

CIBC is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada’s (DAAC) AdChoices program. AdChoices is a self-regulated program for companies participating in online interest-based advertising. The program aims to give Canadians more information and choices about the advertising they get. To learn more about this program, visit [youradchoices.caOpens a new window in your browser.](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)

To opt out of interest-based advertising from some or all AdChoices program participants, use the [AdChoices’ Opt-Out Tool (for browser data)Opens a new window in your browser](https://www.adobe.com/ca/privacy/opt-out.html). This page will scan all of the advertising cookies held on your browser, and a check box will appear under the opt-out column beside companies that are using cookies while you browse sites. To manage your preferences and opt out, check the box (or boxes) and select submit. [AdChoices’ Mobile AppChoices tool (for app data)Opens a new window in your browser](http://youradchoices.ca/appchoices/) also lets you opt out of cross-app data collection for the purposes of interest-based advertisements.

CIBC also works with the Adobe Marketing Cloud to provide interest-based advertisements. To opt out from receiving these types of advertisements and from Adobe Analytics, [set your preferences directly through AdobeOpens a new window in your browser](https://www.adobe.com/ca/privacy/opt-out.html). You can opt out of interest-based advertising, under the “Adobe interest-based ads” section, and you can opt-out from ad tracking through the “Adobe websites” section.

To opt out of interest-based Google advertisements, [set your preferences using Google’s Ad SettingsOpens a new window in your browser](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCjjsAkjXWYv-KMyXPk4dTr0zDksoF4gco2eNLcpFIoIv9qjgbW8SDms0ETLRbd8tdXoAdqt8UnQz3_r4FkGiFQDWjoptM1QwIT5xelLyqwUJd3XA_s&hl=en). You can also opt out of Google Analytics with [Google’s opt-out browser add-onOpens a new window in your browser](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

If you opt-out of interest-based advertising, you may still get CIBC advertising, but it won't be tailored to you.

**Location information:**

CIBC cannot collect or use certain types of location information from geolocation or proximity technologies on your mobile device if the location services on your mobile device are disabled. Mobile devices allow users to disable location services through menu options. Consult your mobile device provider for more information.

**Information on your device:**

The ability to collect certain personal information is controlled by your device. You can control access to this information through your device settings. For example, your device may control the ability to provide access to your contacts, photos and camera. If you choose not to provide access to information on your device, some services may not operate effectively. Refer to the documentation for your device regarding how to allow or block the collection of certain device information. If you have installed our mobile app and wish to stop receiving push notifications, you can change the settings on your mobile device.

##   
Changes to our Digital Privacy Statement

This Digital Privacy Statement may be updated from time to time, in order to reflect changes in our digital information practices. The most recent version will be available online at www.cibc.com. We encourage you to periodically check our Digital Privacy Statement to ensure that you are aware of the most recent version.
